字幕校对+特效: 月亮花@MySiLU思路高清
91，92…
Ninety-one,92...
-就下面 -哪儿？如果被他们抓到…
-It's down there.  -Where? If they catch us...
那儿有上万瓶好酒
There's a million bottles of booze in there.
少个一两瓶不会被发现的
You think they're gonna miss one?
现在顺风，先生
Weather is with us,sir.
几个小时后就能到港
We arrive in port in a couple of hours.
很好
Very good.
谢谢夸奖，先生
You're welcome,sir.
哥们，我从没闻过这样的味道 比厕所闻到的还糟
Man,I never smelt anything like this. Not even when you're in the crapper.
哦，怎么？难到你的屎闻起来能像玫瑰花？
Oh,what,your shit smells like roses?
嘿，看
Hey,look.
我来帮你一把
I'll give you a hand.
-记得你说过这是酒 -那是文件上说的
-Thought you said it was booze.  -That's what the papers said.
船长，有人进入了底层，看
Captain,we have a breach in lower level. Look.
-哪个区？ -101
-Which section?  -101.
妈的，你去掌舵
Fuck. Take the wheel.
-是，先生 -妈的
-Yes,sir.  -Fuck.
关门！戴上防毒面具
Close the door! Get the masks.
哦靠
Holy shit.
把他们处理了
Take care of them.
-早上好 -请出示护照
-Morning.  -Passport,please.
海上很颠簸吧？
Rough seas?
海还挺平稳的，聚会有点吵，你懂的
The sea was smooth. The party was a bit rough,if you know what I mean.
-伊比沙岛（位于地中海西部） -是的
-Ibiza.  -Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
小时候，爸爸经常带我去钓鱼
When I was a kid,my father used to take me fishing.
我一直不明白他怎么会知道哪里有鱼
Never could figure out how he knew where the fish were.
他说鱼在哪儿，鱼就一定在那儿
They were always exactly where he said they would be.
安全检查
Security check.
我看上去像危险分子吗？
Do I look like a security risk?
请下车，带上你的证件到办公室走一趟
Please step out of the car and bring your documents to the office.
先生，我的证件就在这儿
My documents are right here,sir.
但电脑在办公室
The computer is in the office.
她的也是
Her too.
她睡着了
She's sleeping.
-带上她的证件 -好的，当然
-With her documents.  -Okay,sure.
什么鬼东西？
快点，鱼要脱钩了
Come on. You're gonna lose it.
快了，长官，快了
Close,inspector,you're close.
是条大鱼，向左，向左
That's a big one. Go left,go left.
别让它跑了
Don't let him get away.
快钓上来了
You're close.
向左，向左！向右！
Go left,go left! Go right!
一定是条白鲸，需要帮忙吗？
Must be Moby Dick you hooked. Need some help?
不，谢谢，弗兰克
No,thank you,Frank.
你还没出生的时候，我就在这片水域钓鱼了
I have been fishing these waters since before you were born.
你差点就钓到了，长官，就差一点儿
You were close,inspector. You were close.
幸好我们法国人都有很强的幽默感
Good thing that we French have such a highly developed sense of humor.
恕我直言，法国人认为杰瑞・刘易斯是个天才 （美国著名喜剧演员、影视剧以及 舞台剧演员、电影制作人、剧本家和导演）
With all due respect,the French think Jerry Lewis is a genius.
-杰瑞・刘易斯是个天才 -不过迪恩更是天才 （50年代-70年代唯一同时成功地横跨电影 音乐、电视及舞台等领域的喜剧演员）
-Jerry Lewis is a genius.  -Dean was the genius.
不，迪恩只是拿着瓶酒，叼根香烟站在那里
No,Dean just stood there with a drink and a cigarette.
我的意思是他可以让所有人都捧腹大笑
My point exactly. Anyone can fall down and get a laugh.
多少人可以做到？ 只是站在那里，抽着烟，拿着酒
How many people can do it standing still with a drink and a cigarette?
喂？
喂，我是塔可尼
好的
恐怕我们的休闲日子得提前结束了
I am afraid our day of leisure is cut short.
马赛那儿现在一团糟
There is a big mess in Marseilles.
一个疯子驾着奥迪横冲直撞
Some madman driving an Audi at impossible speeds.
别看我
Don't look at me.
那是头要我看的第一个地方
That is the first place the chief told me to look.
但是我会告诉他你有完美的不在场证明
But I will tell him you have the perfect alibi.
就像往常一样
As usual.
塔可尼！
Tarconi!
-帮我一把！ -抱歉，弗兰克
-Please!  -I am sorry,Frank.
-这是我们头回钓到！ -是的，是的
-It's our first bite!  -Yeah,yeah.
-拜托 -嗯
-Please.  -Yeah.
把船停一下，快点
Stop the boat. Come on.
-不，不行，弗兰克 -快点，拜托了
-No. No,Frank.  -Come on,please.
您此行目的是什么，约翰逊先生？
Purpose of your visit,Mr. Johnson?
业务
Business.
什么样的业务？
What kind of business?
环境保护
Environmental protection.
谢谢
Thank you.
部长先生，明天您将在欧盟会议上致开幕词
Mr. Minister,you're giving the opening address at an EU conference...
主题是工业对敖德萨环境的影响
... on environmental impact of industry in Odessa tomorrow.
-最为关键的一点是什么呢？ -很简单
-What is top on your list of priorities?  -It's a short list.
只有一项：环境及其保护措施
There's only one item: The environment and how to protect it.
在全球经济面临日益增长的压力时期
In the face of increasing pressure...
工业要竞争成功
... for industries to compete successfully in a global economy...
目标有时会和残酷的现实相冲突
... that goal can sometimes come up against some very harsh realities.
当然，再残酷也比不上一个 被污染成不适合居住的地球
Well,not as harsh as a polluted and uninhabitable planet.
先生们，请原谅
Gentlemen,if you'll excuse me now...
我得去拯救树木，让工业家们扫兴
... I have trees to save and industrialists to disappoint.
-您明天的演讲稿 -如何？
-Your speech for tomorrow.  -Any good?
-将会令很多人生气 -太棒了
-It's going to piss off a lot of people.  -Excellent.
喂？
Hello?
部长先生？
Mr. Minister?
你是谁？
Who is this?
我的名字并不重要
My name is not important.
你和国际废弃物管理公司
I've been put in charge of the negotiations...
关于其在乌克兰营业许可的谈判
... you are engaged in with Ecocorp...
现在由我负责
... for issuance of their license to do business in the Ukraine.
你一定是搞错了，先生，不管你叫什么
You must be misinformed,Mr. Whatever-Your-Name-Is.
我已彻底结束了谈判
I've terminated negotiations permanently.
只要你看下信封里的资料
I think you will reconsider that position...
我想你会重新考虑的
... once you have a chance to study the documents in the envelope.
我会再联系
I'll be in touch.
是的，这里发生了事故
Yeah,there's been an accident.
请派救护车来 地址是德拉萨佛雷斯大街8号
Send an ambulance,8 Route de la Falaise.
马尔科姆
Malcolm.
马尔科姆，马尔科姆
Malcolm. Malcolm.
我是问你价钱，这是什么？
I asked you for your price. What is this?
一个可能会对这差事感兴趣的人 这个人会的
A man who might be interested in taking the job. This man will.
我老板说你是这差事的不二人选
My boss said you're the man for the job.
你老板搞错了
Your boss got his facts wrong.
关于我老板你得知道两件事：
Two things you should know about my boss:
他从不会搞错，他也从不接受拒绝
He never gets his facts wrong,he never takes no for an answer.
当然，凡事总有第一次
Well,there's a first time for everything.
但不会是这次
Well,not this time.
你不会真想这么做的
You don't wanna do this.
我想还轮不到你告诉我 什么该做，什么不该做
I don't think you're in a position to tell me what I do and don't wanna do.
你有10秒改变主意
You have 10 seconds to change your mind.
我给你5秒钟拿开你的手
I'll give you five seconds to remove your hand.
马尔科姆，马尔科姆
Malcolm. Malcolm.
听得到我吗？
You hear me?
马尔，我是说过欢迎随时拜访 但并不是说…
Mal,I said drop in anytime,but I didn't mean...
-我无处可去 -放松点好吗?
-Nowhere else to go.  -Just take it easy,okay?
别把我弄出去
Don't move me from the car.
-我只是在救护车来之前，帮你弄得舒服点 -不要叫救护车
-It's just get you comfortable till the ambulance arrives.  -No ambulance.
你需要医生，你中枪了，我处理不了这个
You need a doctor,you've been shot. I can't take care of this.
不能离开车子
Not far from car.
放松
Relax.
放松，保持镇定，你马上会得到救治的
Just try to stay calm. We'll have you fixed up in no time.
他在里面，快点，伤得很严重
He's inside. Quick,it's serious.
这边？
先生？
Sir?
-移动他时得小心 -我们知道要怎么做
-You wanna be careful moving him.  -We know our job,okay?
先生，听得到我说话吗？
Sir,can you hear me?
这车…不…
This car...  No...
如果听得到，按一下我的手
If you hear me,press my hand.
这车…
The car...
轻点，小心
差一点
我是在天堂吗？
Am I in heaven?
事实上你处于险境
Actually,you're in a bit of the shit.
那你会帮我脱离吗？
You'll help me out of it?
那取决于你陷得有多深了
That depends on how deep you're in.
-不要相信任何人 -我非常赞同
-Don't trust anyone.  -Couldn't agree with you more.
-来吧 -不！不能离开这车
-Come on.  -No! Don't leave the car!
-这车有什么特殊的吗？ -不是这车
-What's so special about the car?  -Not the car.
等等！
Wait!
我告诉过你
I told you.
不要相信任何人
Don't trust anyone.
我告诉过你
I told you.
我冒昧给你弄了一套西服
I took the liberty of bringing your suit.
那是你工作时穿的，对吗？
It's what you wear when you're working,correct?
是的，但是我没在工作
Correct. But I'm not working.
-你看，老板？我跟您说过 -行了，约瑟夫
-You see,boss? I told you.  -Please,Joseph.
看来首次提出建议，你没用对方法啊
Your approach was not very effective in presenting our proposal the first time.
谢谢
Thank you.
正如我说的
As I was saying...
我们真诚邀见，您却说您没空
... we came to you in good faith. You said you were unavailable.
我们联系了你给号码的那人
We contracted with the man whose number you gave us.
结果证明他无法胜任
He proved to be ineffective.
现在我的这差事还没完成
And now I am left with unfinished business.
在我看来，这是你的责任
The way I see it,you're responsible.
我理解你的意思
I understand your point of view.
但我还是没空
But I'm still unavailable.
老板，我能说点什么吗？
Boss,can I say something?
还有人想张口说话吗？
Anyone else wanna say something?
很好
Good.
给我找个聪明点的
Find me a smarter one.
你有3秒改变主意
You have three seconds to change your mind...
否则让你永远没空
... or you're gonna be permanently unavailable.
有个条件
One condition.
洗耳恭听
I'm listening.
我要开自己的车
I drive my own car.
成交
Deal.
对你的回答早有预料 所以冒昧地把你的车带来了
In anticipation of your answer,we took the liberty of bringing your car.
换了油，对车子进行了调整 把不必要的东西都拿出来了
Changed the oil,gave it a tune-up,took out all the non-essential material.
留下了替换的牌照，喜欢吧
Left the switch-over license plates. Love that.
换上了我们自己的GPS
Replaced the GPS with one of our own.
安装了既定程序的GPS会更有效率的
Preprogrammed. More efficient that way.
我为什么这么坚持 用最适合的人来完成这项任务呢？
Why I was so insistent on using only the best man for this assignment?
我们在玩一个很大的游戏
We're playing in a much larger game here.
不要把它想成只是一份工作，把它当做使命
Don't think of this as just another job. Think of it as a mission.
我很高兴发现 对待工作方面我们有很多共同点
I'm so pleased to find we share the same approach to our work.
我说到做到，就像你一样
I make a deal,that's the deal. Just like you.
你不喜欢问别人名字，我也是 而且我们都很谨慎
You don't like names. Neither do I. We're both precise.
工作以外的事，我们都没有任何兴趣
Neither one of us has any interest in what we're paid to do...
那些是你的规则，对吧？
... beyond what we are paid to do. Those are your rules,right?
你忘了一条
You forgot one.
-我喜欢单干 -我本以为你会喜欢有个伴
-I work alone.  -I thought you might like the company.
我本以为你想我完成使命
Thought you wanted me to complete a mission.
你是对的，的确想
You're right. I do.
等等
Wait.
怎么，你想要改变规则？
What,you wanna change the rules?
每条规则总有例外，今天就破例一下
Every rule has an exception. Let's make one for today.
你说了算
You're the boss.
没问题了吗？
Anything else?
这个首饰，有什么我该知道的吗？
The jewelry. Anything I should know?
记得那些想要炸机的家伙么？
You remember those jokers trying to blow up airliners...
他们把液体偷偷带到飞机上，然后进行混合
... by sneaking liquids through and combining them onboard?
这个原理是一样的，只是更精制些
Same principle,just refined.
离车25英尺
Twenty-five feet from the car...
会亮黄色的灯，表示第一种液体已就绪
... yellow light comes on,signaling the first liquid is ready.
50英尺，亮橙色的灯
Fifty feet,orange.
加入第二种液体
Second liquid flows into the chamber.
75英尺，你会看到亮红色的灯
Seventy-five feet,you're gonna see red.
你们可以出发了
Time to go.
这部电话被设定只能拨一个号码，我的号码
This phone is programmed to call only one number,mine.
过了向北的第一个收费站，给我打电话清楚了吗？
When you pass the first toll on the road going north,call me,all right?
这是油钱和食物的钱
Money for gas and food.
还有其他问题吗？
Any other questions?
你可以系上安全带吗？
Would you mind buckling your seat belt?
难道你不告诉我这究竟是怎么一回事吗？
Don't suppose you wanna tell me what this is all about?
很好
Great.
海洋珍珠号请求货物清关
Ocean Pearl requesting cargo clearance.
文件已送至环保署
The papers are with the environmental agency.
抛锚等候停泊
Drop anchor and wait to dock.
-他们一签署，我们就通知你们 -好的
-We'll inform you when they're signed.  -Okay.
我知道你是怎么回事
I know what happened to you.
但不知道弗兰克是怎么回事？
But what happened to Frank?
情报局的梅德维德上校已收到所有的信息
Colonel Medved over at Intelligence has been given all the information.
他知道那是头等大事
He knows it's top priority.
他想让您知道，他会派最得力的人负责此事
He wants you to know he has his best men on it.
他会让此事避开官方渠道
He'll keep it out of official channels.
他建议您尽量争取时间
He suggests you buy as much time as you can.
长官
车能拖去实验室吗？
告诉他们开始吧，这完了我就过去
他说开工
操！
移开！
警察在办公！
听着，我不知道这事你扮演的是什么角色 我也不关心
Look,I don't know what your part in all this is or isn't. And I don't really care.
但既然你先加入，知道的定比我多
You were here first,you know more than I do...
把你知道的告诉我
... download me on what you know.
我什么都不知道
I know nothing.
你怎么认识马尔科姆的？
How did you know Malcolm?
我不认识
I didn't.
不久前你差点就和他死在车上了，你不认识？
You just happened to end up in a car with a man you don't know?
我现在也和一个我不认识的男人坐在车上
I'm now in a car with man I don't know.
你不是该打电话了吗？
Aren't you supposed to make a call?
很高兴接到你的电话
Nice to hear from you.
客套话就免了，把密码给我
You can skip the pleasantries. Just give me the code.
到了再打给我
Call me when you arrive.
布达佩斯那儿有什么？
What's in Budapest?
菜炖牛肉，啤酒
Goulash. Beer.
很好
All right.
我们重新来过，从自我介绍开始
Let's rewind here,start with the proper introductions.
你办事不是从不问姓名的吗？
What happened to the rule of no names?
那条规则暂时先放一放
I'm suspending that rule for the moment.
我叫弗兰克・马丁
I'm Frank Martin.
你的名字是？
And your name is?
为什么一定要问我名字？
What matters,my name?
好吧，眼下我们是一根绳上的蚂蚱
Well,we're in this situation together.
不
No.
我们俩都戴着带有爆炸装置的手镯坐在这儿 目的地相同
We're sitting here with two exploding bracelets on,going to the same place.
这就叫坐在一条船上
I'd call that being in the same situation.
错了，他们会杀了你
It's not. They are going to kill you.
我知道
I'm aware of that.
十有八九，他们杀了我之后，你就是下一个
In all probability,after they kill me,you're next on the list.
现在，想要保命，我就需要点帮助
Now,if I'm gonna keep that from happening,I'm gonna need a little help.
首先，我们有这个难题
From the top. We have this problem.
你认为我不知道这个是难题吗？
You think I don't know it's a problem?
我看上去很白痴吗？
I look stupid to you?
我没这么说过
I didn't say you were stupid.
但是我们确实有个难题
But we have a problem
在解决这个难题方面，你不是很协助
and you're not being very helpful in participating in the solution of it.
我不想再说了
I don't want to talk anymore.
好吧
Fine.
你刚才说你叫什么名字？
What did you say your name was?
弗兰克，弗兰克・马丁
Frank. Frank Martin.
弗兰克・马丁
Frank Martin.
瓦伦蒂娜
Valentina.
很高兴认识你
Pleased to meet you.
长官，GPS已经被拆掉了
长官？
没错，GPS已被拆了
国际废弃物管理公司的人到了
The gentlemen from Ecocorp are here.
带他们进来
Show them in.
先生们
Gentlemen.
部长先生
Mr. Minister.
很感谢您在匆忙间能重新考虑我们的建议
We'd like to thank you for reconsidering our proposal
想不考虑都难
-on such short notice.  -You make it very hard not to.
恩，是的，我们向来不接受拒绝
Well,yes. We do have a reputation of not taking no for an answer.
合约在这儿
Here are the contracts.
一切准备就绪
All in order.
我们被告知船队不能清关
We were told the ships couldn't be cleared
除非得到您的亲笔签名
unless you personally signed off on them.
船队？
Ships?
我以为只有一条船
I thought there was only one.
哦，好吧，是这样的
Oh,well,here's the thing.
为了使这次冒险更具利润
In order to make the venture more profitable
我们需要大量处理原料
we need to process the material in a volume that makes sense.
现在我们谈论的船只有多少？
How many ships are we talking about?
加上港口等候清关的，总共有8条
Plus the one in the port waiting on clearance,eight.
8条
Eight.
今年
This year.
保护环境是项长期的承诺
Protecting the environment is a long-term commitment.
您说过，不是吗？
You've said so yourself,haven't you?
我明天在敖德萨还会说
And I will do again tomorrow in Odessa
到时我再签
where I will sign these.
我们非常希望今天就能解决
We were really hoping to settle this today.
我要再看看，后面还有些附录
I want to review them,now that there are some addendums.
对这样的长期承诺来说
Twenty-four hours doesn't make a difference
24小时并不能改变什么，不是吗？
on such a long-term commitment,will it?
是的，当然不能
No,of course not.
那么我们明天敖德萨见，早上九点
Then I will see you tomorrow in Odessa. Let's say 9 a.m.
好的
Yes.
好的，我等着
Okay,I'll stay.
-但是原料正在四处泄漏 -然后呢？
-But the material is leaking everywhere.  -And?
-我们会瞒不住的 -我会处理的，给我点时间
-We won't be able to hide it.  -I'll take care of it,just give me some time.
如果他们来检查
If ever they check...
别紧张，交易很快就会达成的
Easy. The deal will be closed very soon.
24小时，不能再拖了
Twenty-four hours. No more.
-喂？ -我为你们又争取了24小时
-Yes?  -I've bought you another 24 hours.
到明天早上9点
You have until tomorrow,9 a.m.
那时间应该绰绰有余
That should be more than enough time.
有线索了吗？
Do you have a lead?
不止有线索
Better than a lead.
还有一台定位器
A location.
长官
国际刑警认出了车牌
是通往罗多夫路上的一台测速器拍到的
联系我们的德国朋友们
是，可我要说什么呢？
期待与我共进晚餐吧
我饿了
I'm hungry.
再有100公里就有啤酒和香肠了
We're 100 kilometers from beer and sausage.
我不喜欢香肠
I don't like sausage.
那喜欢什么？
What would you like?
小牛肉
Veal.
和胡萝卜一起烤
Roast,with carrots...
还有甜菜
and beets.
放在肉汁里，再配上马德拉产的白葡萄酒 （大西洋的群岛名）
In gravy,with Madeira in stock.
不来份前菜吗？
Nothing to start?
一份色拉
A salad.
蔬菜拌上香脂
Greens tossed with balsamic.
摩德纳的香脂 （意大利北部，博洛尼亚西北偏西的一座城市）
From Modena.
陈年的？
Aged?
当然，陈年的
Of course,aged.
甜点呢？
And for dessert?
萨克大蛋糕
Sachertorte.
要加上生奶油吗？
With whipped cream or without?
要
With.
喝什么？
To drink?
葡萄酒
Wine.
托卡伊葡萄酒？ （匈牙利的托卡伊葡萄酒，自1650年问世以来 一直以其独一无二顶级优质而享誉世界）
Tokaj,perhaps?
要冰的
Ice wine.
当然
Of course.
-你在干嘛？ -去见一个珠宝专家
-What are you doing?  -Seeing a man about some jewelry.
他偏离了设定路线
He's gone off the reservation.
派人叫他回归路线
Send someone to get him back on.
别杀了他
Don't kill him.
弗兰克，见到你真高兴，我的朋友
Frank. It's so good to see you,mein Freund.
我也是，奥托
Good to see you too,Otto.
你没提过要带伴来
You didn't mention you bring company.
不是真的伴
It's not really company.
这…
It's...
很复杂
complicated.
和你一起总会很复杂
With you,it's always complicated. But you can tell me about it...
我准备了美味的土豆色拉炸排条 我们可以边吃边聊
over a nice schnitzel with Kartoffelsalat I have prepared.
嘿，奥托，你知道我喜欢你的炸排条
Hey,Otto,you know I love your schnitzel
但是我们得先弄掉这个
but we need to get rid of this first.
噢，这是自由式二元磁性分解技术
Binary free-form magnetic-resolution technology.
拜托，说英文，奥托
English,please,Otto.
五角大楼通过他们的一家附属前台公司
There's a program the Pentagon has funded
资助开发了一套程序
through one of their subsidiary front companies
就是根据磁引力理论
that's been experimenting with this new kind of weaponry
测试的一种新式武器
based on the theory of magnetic attraction.
这是限制级机密
Very hush-hush stuff.
没想到你还能搞到五角大楼限制级机密
I didn't realize you were in the loop on the Pentagon hush-hush.
当你在互联网上漫步时
You wouldn't believe what you can discover
你会惊讶自己所发现的东西
when you left your fingers walking through the Internet.
你想看看入侵伊朗的计划吗？
You wanna see the invasion plans for Iran?
也许下次吧
Maybe some other time.
现在，我们得把这玩意儿弄下来 不然我会被轰到伊朗去的
Right now we need to get this thing off without blowing myself to Iran.
我不想拿细节来烦你
I don't wanna bother you with the details
但通常这儿附近会有个发射器
but usually there's a transmitter plate close by.
你不必这么做
You should not be doing this.
起先你不说，现在却提建议
First you don't talk,now you offer advice.
不是建议，是警告
Not advice. A warning.
就算是，你不觉得这警告迟了点吗？
Well,a little late for warnings,don't you think?
我同意
I agree with you.
你偏离路线了
You're off course.
-我继续吗？ -是的，你继续
-Should I?  -Yeah,you should.
听着，伙计们
Look,fellas
车子有点问题，需要检查一下
some things in the car were a bit off,needed checking.
男人得和他驾驶的车一样棒 这是职业经验
In my profession,a man is only as good as the car he drives.
你照顾好车，车就会照顾好你
You take care of the car,the car will take care of you.
老板说，“回到原路线”
The boss says," Back on the road."
弗兰克？
Frank?
继续
Keep at it.
回车上，弗兰克
Back in the car,Frank.
不
No.
-找到了吗？ -没有
-Find it?  -Not yet.
你是最厉害的？
You're the smart one?
不，我是最大个的
No. I'm the big one.
不再是大家伙了，不是吗？
Not so big anymore,are you?
找到了
Found it.
-发射器 -你能移除吗？
-The transmitter.  -Can you remove it?
接着电线
It's wired.
如果移除就会爆炸
If I do: it comes boom.
打得不错
You fight good.
但领带打得够烂的
But your tie bad.
你到哪儿去？
Where are you going?
累了
Tired.
那就是我更愿意和车打交道的原因
That's why I prefer to deal with cars.
英雄所见
That makes two of us.
他们醒了之后，我要怎么办？
What do you want me to do when they... ? When they wake up?
或许最好挨下来放个假
Probably best to take the rest of the day off.
我很不爽
I'm not amused.
如果你死的话，你会更不爽
You'd be less amused if you ended up dead.
你想要我死的话我早就死了 可你要我活着
If you wanted me dead,I'd be dead. You need me alive.
想要我完成这件任务，我需要一些解释
You want me to complete the job,I need some clarification.
我在听
I'm listening.
单独的
In person.
是单独的
We've already done in person.
显然，我并不满意
Well,not to my satisfaction,apparently.
现在，我是否满意是你首要关心的问题
Right now,my satisfaction should be your main concern.
同一地点，1小时后，等我电话
Same place. One hour. Wait for my call.
喂？
Hello?
你让我很失望
You've disappointed me.
你不会是第一个，也不会是最后一个
You won't be the first and you won't be the last.
-我告诉过你我想单独做这事 -没必要，你瞧…
-I told you I wanted to do this in person.  -That won't be necessary. You see...
在我们开始谈话的时候
since our little chat at the beginning
我就在想，我并不需要 最棒的人来完成这项平凡的任务
I've been thinking I don't need the best for this mundane assignment.
任何一个有驾驶证的白痴都可以完成
Any idiot with a driver's license will do.
引用伟大的美国人唐纳德・特朗普的话 （美国公司总裁、企业家、电视人和作家）
So in the words of the great American,Donald Trump:
很抱歉，你被解雇了
I'm sorry,but you're fired.
你是谁？
Who are you?
-你的新司机 -我要以前的那个
-Your new chauffeur.  -I want the old one back.
他就要被炸成碎片了
He's about to go to pieces.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
睡得怎么样？
How was your nap?
很安稳，你电话打得怎么样了？
Restful. How was your phone call?
很短，系好你的安全带
Brief. Fasten your seat belt.
塔可尼
Tarconi.
是我
It's me.
我就在想你什么时候打给我
I was wondering when you would call.
我在忙
I've been busy.
让我猜猜，在布达佩斯？
Let me guess. In Budapest?
你也在忙
You've been busy too.
和你联系没有问题，弗兰克
Never a problem keeping that way with a friend like you,Frank.
那我就不多说了，告诉我你所知道的
So I don't have to be redundant,tell me what you know.
在布达佩斯也有辆黑色的梅赛德斯
There is a black Mercedes also in Budapest.
很可能不归你的朋友所有
Probably not occupied by friends of yours.
那是我所知道的，现在告诉我你所知道的
That is what I know. Now tell me what you know.
我有两个包在后备箱，一个女孩在前座
I have two bags in the back and a girl in the front.
我猜是俄国人
Russian,I think.
我不知道她跟这一切有什么关系
I don't know what she has to do with anything.
你有试着问过她吗？
Have you tried asking her?
-我会没想过？ -抱歉
-Now,why didn't I think of that?  -Sorry.
你一定问过了，她怎么说？
Of course you've asked. And she says?
我会死
I'm going to die.
典型的俄国人
Typical. Russians.
他们太悲观了
They are so dark.
我记得，在学校的时候，读着陀思妥耶夫斯基的书 （19世纪俄国文坛上一颗耀眼的明星，代表作《罪与罚》）
I remember,in school,reading Dostoyevsky and thinking
然后想，这些人什么时候才会笑呢？
when do these people laugh?
一页又一页
One page after the other
写着令你无法相信的痛苦和折磨，弗兰克
misery and suffering like you wouldn't believe,Frank.
长官，我们可以忽略这节文学课吗？ 我这儿灯正在闪
Inspector,can we save the literature lesson? I'm blinking here.
是电码吗？
Is that code?
不，是他们给我们带上的类似手镯的饰物
No,it's some bracelet they accessorized us with.
设定了如果我们离车太远就会爆炸
Wired to explode if we get too far from the car.
他们？
They?
是些美国人
Some American.
可以再详细点吗？一个名字或一个号码？
Can you be more specific? A name? A number?
没了
Nothing.
你怎么总能镇定自若呢，弗兰克？
Why do you always make it so easy,Frank?
是本能
It's my nature.
你在哪儿？我来找你
Where are you? I will come there.
这可不是个好主意，我被看得很紧
That's not a good idea. They have me on a short leash.
如果你不告诉我些东西，我就帮不上什么忙
I can't be of much help if you do not give me something.
你离电脑近吗？
How close are you to a computer?
喂，弗兰克？
Yes,Frank?
被扔在市场上，是不是很不爽
That wasn't very nice,back there in the market.
破坏规则的人是你，不是我
You were the one who broke the rules,not me.
我承认
Point well taken.
我们扯平了，重新来过怎么样？
That makes us even. What say we start with a clean slate?
所以这通电话表示握手言和咯？
So this call is about kiss-and-make-up,then?
差不多吧
More or less.
你有办法去掉这手镯
You have what I need to get the bracelet off...
我有你需要快递的包裹
... I have the packages you need delivered.
这儿是新坐标，2-6-12
Here are the new coordinates,then: 2-6-12.
那可以带你
That'll take you to the place...
到结束交易的地方
... where we can have a conclusion to this business.
我很期待
I look forward to it.
弗兰克
Frank.
你查到了吗？
Did you get it?
查到了信号，给我们一点时间
Got the signal. Give us a little time...
我们就能查到他的号码和位置
... and we should have his number and location.
你的新电话，先生
Your new phone,sir.
-还有别的事吗？ -没有
-Anything else?  -No.
弗兰克，你知道这个信号要带你去哪儿吗？
Frank,do you know where the signal is taking you?
我知道那儿有家饭店，那儿的鱼你从没吃过
I know restaurant there. Fish like you never had.
和小胡萝卜一起烤，还有黑胡椒
Roasted with small carrots and black pepper.
罗马尼亚的葡萄酒不是很好
Romanian wine,not so good.
作为最后的晚餐，可能差了点
But for the last meal,could be worse.
你应该乐观点
You really should begin to think more positive.
我是现实主义者
I'm realist.
我朋友是对的，他说你悲观绝望
My friend was right when he said you were doom and gloom.
什么意思？
What means "doom and gloom"?
你只看到恐惧和害怕
You know,you only see the horrible and the terrible.
你的朋友，他怎么知道？他又不认识我
Your friend,where does he get this? He doesn't know me.
他只是大体描述了一下，一个俄国人
He was talking about you in general. Russians,as a people.
我不是俄国人，我是乌克兰人
I'm not Russian. I'm Ukrainian.
抱歉
Excuse me.
不接受，我们不是同一类人
Not excused. We're different people. We're different here...
我们这儿，那儿都不同
... and here.
个人觉得，你还是有点乐观的
Me,personally,I think there's a little bit of an optimist in you.
你如何下的定论？你又不了解我
How you can make such a statement? You don't know me.
哦，我看见你在化妆
Well,I see you're putting makeup on.
如果你确定我们要死，为什么还要多此一举呢？
If you were so convinced we was gonna die,why bother?
要漂亮和死有什么关系吗？
What does looking good have to do with dying?
嘿
Hello.
那是什么？
What's that?
伊比沙岛的特产，你想来一颗吗？
Souvenirs from Ibiza. Do you want one?
不，谢谢，你也不要吃 我们需要保持清醒
No,thank you. And neither do you. We need to stay sharp.
好的
Okay.
你要保持清醒
You stay sharp.
我也要，你怎么说的？乐观？
I stay,how you say? Optimist?
把它给我，给我，把药丸给我！
Give me that. Give me that thing. Give me the pill!
给我
Give me that...
天呢
Jesus.
好极了
Great.
-真棒 -来吧，弗兰克・马丁，高兴点儿
-Just great.  -Come on,Frank Martin,lighten up.
我要高兴？药丸发作的时候要怎么办？
I should? How about when those pills hit?
你会high得跟他妈的圣诞树似的
You're gonna be lighting up like a goddamn Christmas tree.
那会很不错
That would be nice.
无聊，无聊，无聊？
Boring. Boring. Boring?
哦，耶
Oh,yeah.
你应该呆车里
You should stay in the car.
你要我在车里尿尿吗？
You want me to pee in car?
好吧，去吧
Okay. Go on.
记住
You remember.
不行
Don't.
哦，不是吧
Oh,no.
-别喝了，好吗？ -为什么？我又不开车
-Stop,all right?  -Why? I don't drive.
我只是想开心点
I want to have fun.
我想要开心点 你也应该开心点而不是那么严肃
I want to be happy. You should try happy instead of so serious.
保持乐观很重要，就像你说的，不是吗？
It's important to stay positive,like you say,yeah?
-和我一起喝，弗兰克 -我不想喝
-Drink with me,Frankie.  -I don't want a drink.
现在谁是悲观绝望的？
Now who is all gloomy and doomy?
我说的对吗？悲观绝望？
I say it right? Gloomy doomy?
够了，快上车
Come on,get in the car.
我是自由的，就像鸟一样
I am free,like a bird.
是那个女孩！快点！快开！
The girl! Come on! Faster!
-我弄丢了我的朋友！ -我会再给你买一瓶的
-I have lost my friend!  -I'll buy you a new one.
知道为什么有辆车在我们屁股后面吗？
Have any idea why we have a car on our ass?
我不知道，我不在乎
I don't know. I don't care.
-你介意？ -起先你说我是悲观绝望的
-You mind?  -First you say I'm doom and gloom...
现在你又叫我不要开心？变来变去
... and now you tell me do not be happy? Make up your mind.
-喂，弗兰克？ -我想我们已达成了协议
-Yes,Frank?  -I thought we had an agreement.
是的
We do.
这和后面的车没关系吧
It had nothing to do with a car on my ass.
我跟那没有关系，是和你有仇的人吧？
I don't have anything to do with that. Someone else has issues with you?
可能吧
Likely.
我想是其他势力的人在办事
What I think is that there are other forces at work here.
让我查一下，看看我能查到些什么
Let me check into it,see what I can find out.
那这期间我要做什么？
What do I do in the meantime?
开快点
Drive faster.
他到底在干嘛？
What the hell is he doing?
那儿！
There!
他在那儿！
He's down there!
我饿了
I'm hungry.
早该想到买三明治而不是伏特加
Should have thought about a sandwich,not vodka.
看！
Look!
我刚才不饿，而是口渴
I wasn't hungry then,I was thirsty.
为什么对我那么小气？
Why you are so mean to me?
-我不是小气，我是全神贯注 -什么叫全神贯注？
-I'm not being mean. I'm preoccupied.  -What means "preoccupied"?
意思是全神贯注
That means preoccupied.
打轮胎！快！抓住他！
Shoot the tires! Come on! Get him!
-往下面！ -打他！
-Get down!  -Shoot him!
混蛋！
Bloody hell!
快！
Faster!
阻止那辆车！
Stop the car!
哦，妈的！
Oh,shit!
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
你太紧张了
You're so tense.
不用你说
You don't say.
我帮你放松，如何？
I make you relax,okay?
-好的 -我很在行的
-Yeah.  -I'm good at this.
消除紧张
Making tense go away.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
我想在临死前再感受一次性爱
I want to feel sex one more time before I die.
你不想吗？
Don't you?
这和你还有死有什么关系？
What is it with you and dying?
我有什么问题吗？
There is something wrong with me?
我不性感吗？
Am I not sexy?
不，你很性感
Yeah,you're sexy.
你是同性恋
You're the gay.
不，我不是同性恋
Nope,I am not the gay.
我不介意
I don't mind.
我不是，好伐？
I'm not,okay?
那是什么问题？
Then what's the problem?
你有没有想过，也许我没心情呢？
Did it ever occur to you that maybe I'm not in the mood?
-我想规则是不能打开包裹的 -是的
-I thought rule is don't open package.  -It is.
如果你违反了规则，还要规则干嘛？
Why you have rules if you break them?
我也一直在问自己同样的问题
I keep asking myself the same thing.
电话簿
Phone books.
-你是那个包裹 -没错
-You're the package.  -Yes.
应该早点说
Could have said something.
-有区别吗？ -有
-Would it make a difference?  -Yes.
你要干嘛？
Now what are you doing?
你知道，在车库后面
You know,back in garage...
当你脱掉衣服的时候，让我觉得很兴奋
... it was very turn-on to me when you take off your clothes.
我当时正竭力不让五个白痴抓到
I was trying to keep five cretins from caving my head in.
我不觉得有什么好兴奋的
I don't see the turn-on in that.
你认为只有男人会对脱衣舞兴奋吗？
You think it's only man gets turned on by striptease?
我不想事情变成那样，瓦伦蒂娜
I don't like where this is going,Valentina.
你能再为我脱一次吗？
Would you striptease for me again?
把钥匙给我，这不好玩
Give me the keys. This is not funny.
你想要钥匙吗？
You want keys?
我想要你停止玩闹
I want you to stop playing around,is what I want.
也许这是我们最后一次机会玩闹了
Maybe it's last chance to play around for you and for me.
现在不是玩的时间也不是玩的地点
This is not the time or the place for playing.
为什么我会感觉这从来不是时间或地点的问题？
Why do I get feeling with you it's never time or place?
如果我想要分析一下，就会见心理医生
If I wanna get analyzed,I'll see a psychiatrist.
现在，把钥匙给我
Now,give me the keys.
来吧，弗兰克・马丁
Come on,Frank Martin.
和我一起玩吧
Make playtime for me.
行了嘛？够了吗？
All right? That enough?
不够，那不是脱衣舞，弗兰克
Not enough. That is not a striptease,Frank.
脱衣舞是性感的，你知道，扭扭屁股啊
Striptease is sexy. You know,move your ass a little.
来吧，弗兰克・马丁
Come on,Frank Martin.
你想要钥匙吗？
You want keys?
我想要脱衣舞
I want strip.
让我做这些，你知道会有什么后果吗？
You know what I'm gonna do to you for making me do this?
打我？
Spank me?
那只是开始
For starters.
-把我捆起来吗？ -你喜欢那样，不是吗？
-Tie me up?  -You'd like that,wouldn't you?
我喜欢暴力
I like the rough stuff.
真的？
Really?
哦，但是不要太暴力了
Oh,but not too rough.
交易是脱衣舞交换钥匙
Deal was a striptease for the keys.
新的交易，吻我交换钥匙
New deal. Kiss me for the keys.
用心点
Like you mean it.
你有用心吻过一个人吗，弗兰克？
Do you ever kiss like you mean it,Frank?
我想也许没有
I'm thinking maybe not.
我想你独自生活
I'm thinking you live alone.
无论在家还是在外
Inside and outside.
我想你不是惧怕死亡
Thinking it is not dying you're afraid of.
而是惧怕生活
It's living.
和我一起生活吧
Live with me.
就这一次
Just this once.
就这会儿，和我一起活着
Just this moment. Live with me.
-他现在在什么位置？ -我们失去了他的信号
-What's his position?  -We lost him.
他进了山区，我们接收不到那里的信号
He headed into the mountains. We can't get reception up there.
侵入军用卫星
Hack into one of the military satellites.
喂
Yes.
您认为我们是在玩游戏吗，部长先生？
You think we're playing games here,Mr Minister?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我在说一辆黑色轿车 载满了一群你的无能手下
I'm talking about a black car full of your incompetent operatives.
再有这样的举动 你就别想再见到你的女儿了
One more move like that and you will never see your daughter again.
我要听听她的声音
I want to hear her voice.
等合约签好传过来之后吧
When the contract is signed and delivered.
听不到她的声音，我是不会签字的
I will not sign until I hear her voice.
你现在没有强硬的资格，部长先生
You are in no position to play hardball,Mr Minister.
那你也没有，约翰逊先生
Well,neither are you,Mr Johnson.
没错，我知道你是谁
Yes,I know who you are.
我可以向你保证，如果我女儿有任何闪失
And I can assure you,if anything happens to my daughter...
我会动用我所有的权力
... I will use all the power I have.
抓到你，用最可怕的方式让你偿还
I will hunt you down and make you pay in a most hideous way for this.
我们得行动了
We have to move now.
接电话，弗兰克，快接
Pick up,Frank. Pick up.
我在伊比沙岛度假
I'm in Ibiza. Making holiday.
有人递给我杯香槟
Someone hands me glass of champagne.
我喝了
I drink.
然后觉得有点儿不舒服
Then I don't feel so good.
我去了趟厕所，然后我醒来就在车上了
I go to bathroom,and next thing,I'm awake in the car.
我问他，“这是哪儿” 他说他只是个送货的
I ask him,"Where is this?" He tells me he's just a transporter.
他车开得很棒
He's pretty good driver.
当然没有你好
Not like you good.
我和他说 “求你了，我父亲是个有权有势的人
I tell him,"Please. My father a really powerful man.
很有影响力，认识很多人 让我给他打个电话吧”
Big influence. Knows a lot of people. Let me call him."
他害怕了，他以前从没做过
He's afraid. He's never done this before.
这本来应该很简单 载人，离开，轻轻松松拿到钱
It's supposed to be simple. Pick up,drop off. Easy money.
有人告诉他，不能打电话，不能离开车
He's been told no calls,never leave car.
但是我说服了他
But I convince him.
我打了电话
I call.
但是我还没来得及和我父亲说我们在哪儿
But before I say to my father where we are...
快上车，快！
Inside the car. Come on!
我们逃脱了，但是…
We get away,but...
有人朝我们开枪，为什么？
There's people shooting at us. Why?
他们为什么要朝我们开枪？
Why they shooting at us?
他说他们开枪是因为我们没有按照计划行事
He says they shoot because we didn't go according to plan.
我说，“好吧，那是个老计划 现在的新计划呢？”
I said,"Okay,that's the old plan. What's new plan?"
他说他有个朋友
He says he has a friend.
接着就遇到了你
And then I met you.
见到你，我就觉得安全了
And then I feel it's gonna be okay.
你甚至都不认识我
You didn't even know me.
我当然不认识你
Of course I don't know you.
我是在说感觉，不是认不认识
I talk about feelings,not knowing.
如果你有那种感觉，你表达的方式真是有趣
Well,if you was feeling that way,you sure had a funny way of showing it.
对女人来说，有点神秘感会更好
Better for a woman to have a little mystery to her.
不是吗？
No?
不是
No.
没错，只是一点点
Yes. Just a little.
回到雷达监控上了，先生
He's back on the radar,sir.
-喂 -你到底在哪儿？
-Yeah.  -Where the hell are you?
在去布加勒斯特的路上
On the way to Bucharest.
地点换了
Not any longer.
新坐标：3-7-13
New coordinates: 3-7-13.
打扰一下，部长先生
Excuse me,Mr. Minister.
对不起，就一分钟
Sorry,just a minute.
我是塔可尼督察，来自马赛
Inspector Tarconi,from Marseilles.
额，准确来说，也不是马赛
Well,not exactly Marseilles...
-是马赛东面的一个小镇 -你想说什么，督察？
-... but a small town to the east...  -What do you want,inspector?
-和你谈谈 -我没时间
-A word with you.  -I have no time.
是关于您女儿的
It's about your daughter.
敖德萨，弗兰克，我的故乡
Odessa,Frank. My country.
你带我回家了，谢谢你
You take me home. Thank you.
怎么不去布加勒斯特了？
What happened to Bucharest?
-计划变了 -变得好，我更喜欢敖德萨
-Change of plans.  -It's a good change. I prefer Odessa.
是嘛
Yeah.
我倒是期待着鱼和胡萝卜
I was looking forward to that fish with the carrots myself.
哦，这儿会更好的
Oh,it's much better here.
-你知道基辅鸡吗？ -当然
-You know chicken Kiev?  -I do.
我知道这儿有家餐馆
I know restaurant here.
是世界上最棒的
Best in the world.
鸡肉鲜美，当黄油溢出来的时候
The chicken's so fresh. And the butter,when it's coming out...
你不敢相信，美味极了
Like you cannot believe,it's so nice.
你知道我现在是什么感觉吗？
You know what I feel like now?
饿的感觉
Hungry.
安全感
Safe.
这会像电影的结局那样 从此过着幸福快乐的生活吗？
It's going to end up like the movies,this happily ever after?
今晚，这一切都将成为回忆
By tonight,this is all gonna be a fading memory.
结局是你和我会在基辅鸡店里坐着笑着
It's gonna be you and me,laughing over chicken Kiev.
骗子
Liar.
部长先生，改主意了
Mr. Minister,an update,please.
一旦跟我女儿通过话，我就会签合同
I am ready to sign the contract once I speak to my daughter.
喂？喂？
Hello? Hello?
准备好笔，我会再电话你的
Have that pen ready. I'll call you back.
-喂 -我们要收网了，弗兰克
-Yeah.  -We are closing the noose,Frank.
好的，收网的时候，确保没人把我拖下车
Well,when it closes,make sure no one tries to drag me out of the car.
你现在知道这是怎么回事了吗？
You know what this is about yet?
这个女孩，她的父亲
The girl. Her father.
和大量的有毒废料有关
Large amounts of toxic waste.
这是场交易，他的签字换他女儿的命
It is a trade. His signature for her life.
我会用我的信誉保证保护她，长官
I have a reputation to uphold here,inspector.
完成送货率是100%
One hundred percent successful delivery rate.
我好像听出来有点儿什么苗头？
Am I detecting a little attachment?
这不是我认识的弗兰克，他有他的规则 不问名字，不牵扯感情
That is not the Frank I know. With his rules,no names,no attachment.
为什么每个人都对我的规则那么感兴趣？
Why is everyone so concerned about my rules?
弗兰克，我一直怀疑 其实你的内心是浪漫的
Frank,I always suspected you are a romantic at heart.
还有别的事吗？
Anything else?
目的地在哪儿？
Where is the rendezvous?
我会再打给你的
I'll call you back.
-喂 -快结束了，弗兰克
-Yeah.  -We're almost at the end,Frank.
-把坐标给我 -没坐标了
-Just give me the coordinates.  -No more coordinates.
就在你现在的路上
The road you're on.
第一个路口左拐
Make your first left.
我想要知道具体到哪儿
I'd like to know where I'm going.
到那儿你就知道了
You'll know when you get there.
别担心，这地方正是我们想带他们来的
Don't worry. We got them right where we want them.
恭喜你，弗兰克
My compliments,Frank.
你的能力果然值得我们信任
Our trust in your abilities was well deserved.
现在你可以请那女孩出来了
Now if you could please send the girl out.
她马上出去
She's coming.
我不出去
I'm not coming.
他们需要你，他们不会杀你的
They need you. They won't kill you.
但是他们会杀了你
But they will kill you.
我像是穿越半个欧洲而死在桥上的人吗？
Do I look like a man who came halfway across Europe to die on a bridge?
像吗？
Do I?
我们没一整天可耗，弗兰克
We don't have all day,Frank.
看他们有很多人
Look how many of them.
都带着抢
They have all the guns.
怎么可能会没事？
How it's gonna be okay?
吃晚饭的时候告诉你
Tell you over dinner.
现在去吧
Now,go.
走
Go.
吻我
Kiss me.
走
Go.
你会害死我的，快走
You're gonna get me killed. Now,go.
抓她，你这混蛋
Get to her,you bastard.
好点了吗，亲爱的？
Better now,darling?
把他干了
Finish him.
不！弗兰克！
No! Frank!
他的爱车将成为他的坟墓
His beloved car will be his grave.
出来他会炸死，呆着他会淹死 我们撤吧
Leaves it,he blows. Stays,he drowns. Let's get out of here.
-塔可尼 -女孩在他们手里
-Tarconi.  -They have the girl.
弗兰克，我们正通过电话信号找他的位置
Frank,we are trying to track him through the phone signal.
-你在哪儿？ -湖里
-Where are you?  -In a lake.
湖？
A lake?
能再具体点吗？
Can you be more specific?
有个水坝
There's a dam.
-水坝？ -我知道那地方，先生
-A dam?  -I know the place,sir.
-多远？ -至少10分钟
-How far?  -Ten minutes at least.
弗兰克，我们将在10分钟内到
Frank,we'll be there in 10 minutes.
能再快点吗？
Can you make it any faster?
-我们尽力 -谢谢
-We'll do our best.  -Thank you.
买所有人的票
Buy tickets for all of us.
到哪儿？
Where to?
不管到哪儿，这半个小时我们得一直移动
Anywhere this train is going. We need to keep moving for half an hour.
为什么不开车绕圈呢？
Why don't we just keep driving around?
这账改天再算
Another day.
先生！在那儿！
Sir! There!
-出去，出去！ -所有人都出去！
-Out. Out!  -Everybody out!
-快 -出去！
-Come on.  -Move!
出去，快！
Move,quick!
-部长先生？ -喂
-Mr. Minister?  -Yes.
有人想和你通话
Someone wants to talk to you.
-爸爸 -你还好吗？
-Papa.  -Are you all right?
不要签
Don't sign.
你还有15分钟的时间
What you have is 15 minutes.
-查出这究竟是怎么回事了吗？ -垃圾
-You ever find out what this is about?  -Garbage.
我们现在谈的是多少垃圾？
How much garbage are we talking?
足够污染半个国家一百年的垃圾
Enough to pollute half the country for a hundred years.
再试一次
Try it again.
作为一个现代女性，你相当无知
For a modern woman,you are very uninformed.
这是个新世界
This is the new world.
不再有什么国家，那是旧想法了
There are no more countries. That's old think.
只有现实的经济效益，利益和损失
There are just economic realities. Profit and loss.
高效和浪费
Efficiency and waste.
要考虑全球，而不是地方
Think global,not local.
去你妈的
Think this.
-喂？ -进展如何？
-Yes?  -Where are we?
就快完事了
We're almost there.
在哪儿？
Where?
这儿，他在一辆火车上
Here. He is on a train.
-我们呢？ -这儿
-And where are we?  -Here.
我们可以在那儿跟火车接头
We can get units there.
这主意不错，就这么办
That's a good idea. Do that.
哦，弗兰克，拜托
Oh,Frank,come on.
部长先生，我向您保证 一切都合乎程序
Mr. Minister,I assure you,everything is in order.
我相信
I'm sure it is.
-如果出了什么问题 -我知道你们会解决的
-If there are any problems...  -I know you will solve them.
现在，让我一个人
Now,if you don't mind...
也许你不相信 但是我的内心其实是和平主义者
You might not believe this,but I am,at heart,a pacifist.
我讨厌暴力
I hate violence.
暴力造成的问题比解决的还多
It creates more problems than it solves.
你知道，这并非我所愿
You know,I never wanted to do any of this.
一个客户问我要结果
A client asked me to obtain a result...
所以我想用最少的流血
... so I went about creating an environment...
获得他想要的结果
... with the least amount of bloodshed.
没人想合作，你不想，第一个司机不想
No one wanted to cooperate. Not you,not the first driver...
你父亲不想，刚死的弗兰克・马丁也不想
... not your father,not the recently deceased Frank Martin.
每个人都想打架
Everyone wanted to fight.
有什么好笑的吗？
What's so funny?
听一个死人说话
Hearing a dead man talking.
再走一步，弗兰克
One more step,Frank.
来啊，再走一步啊
Come on. One more.
看
Look.
结束了
It's over.
8:58了，他签了
Two minutes to 9. He signed.
哦，我的天
Oh,my God.
不，弗兰克，不，不
No,Frank. No,no.
结束了，弗兰克，结束了
It's over,Frank. It's over.
任务完成，你和这女孩自由了
Mission accomplished. You and the girl are free to go.
事实上，你的才能给我留下深刻印象
Matter of fact,I'm so impressed by your talent...
我可以给你提供一个职位
... I'd like to offer you a position.
我想给你提供一个，终身残废
I'd like to offer you one. Permanently disabled.
我讨厌浪费人才
I hate to waste talent.
但是我们真的合不来
But I really don't think we'd make a very good fit.
没错
That's right.
不！
No!
我们是合不来，不过你和这手镯很般配
We wouldn't fit,but you and the bracelet were made for each other.
不，不
No,no.
不！
No!
您是在做件正确的事
You're doing the right thing.
瓦伦蒂娜
Valentina.
我是在天堂吗？
Am I in heaven?
我们更像是在地狱
Looks more like we're in hell.
我不在乎
I don't care.
只要我们能在一起
As long as we're there together.
喂？
Yes?
部长先生，您的女儿在我们这儿了
Mr. Minister,your daughter is in good hands.
谢谢
Thank you.
-你在干嘛？ -就像你说的，做正确的事
-What are you doing?  -What you said,the right thing.
现在，先生们，请见谅 我还有个会要发表演讲
And now,gentlemen. if you'll excuse me,I have a conference to address...
是关于与你们这样的人做生意的危险性
... on the dangers of doing business with people like you.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
船准备好了吗？
Is the launch ready?
-在水上，先生，随时待命 -该走了
-It's on the water,sir,waiting.  -Time to leave.
-带上航海日志 -是
-Grab the log.  -Okay.
我只是不明白
I just don't understand it.
当我还是小男孩的时候，我和我父亲
When I was a boy,my father and I...
一天总能从这儿钓到鱼
... used to pull fish out of this very spot all day long.
时代变了，长官
Times change,inspector.
人也一样
As do people.
你说我？
You referring to me?
我认为这话不对
I don't think that's a very accurate statement.
我还在开同样的车，住同样的房子
I drive the same car,live in the same house.
哦，我不是指你的车子和房子
Oh,I was not referring to your car or your house.
大海真宁静啊
The sea is so restful.
午饭准备好了吗？
Is lunch ready yet?
小姐，事情总有先后次序
Mademoiselle,there is a certain progression to things.
要吃午饭，你得先抓到午饭
In order to eat the lunch,you first have to catch the lunch.
如果我们继续讨论而不集中注意力的话
And if we keep talking instead of concentrating...
我们就什么都钓不到
... we're gonna catch nothing.
我有个更好的主意 为什么我们不跳过抓午饭这一步
I have better idea. Why we don't skip catching of lunch...
直接去吃午饭呢？
... and go right to eating of lunch?
我知道离这儿不远有个很棒的地方
I know wonderful place just up coast from here...
他们炖的鱼超级好吃
... where they make fish stew. Incredible.
他们用番茄和洋葱做作料 加上一点野生薰衣草
They use tomatoes and onions,and little amount of wild lavender.
有什么样的葡萄酒？
What kind of wine?
粉红的，来自南方的酒
Pink. From south.
也许是教皇新堡酒
A Chateauneuf,perhaps.
-冰的 -当然是冰的
-Chilled.  -Of course,chilled.
甜点呢？
And for dessert?